<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="dantran@yahoo.com">Dan T. Tran</author>
    <title>GLVNSJCDB</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Unicode Setup">
      <p>
        One of the best example for using UNICODE in Window 2000 and XP is you
        can create a Microsoft Word document, save it as HTML format, and load
        the file into your web server. Any one (include those using Mac, Windows 9x)
        can view the document without installing any Vietnamese font.  However,
        in order to view a Vietnamese Word document, you must have Vietnamese
        language support in Window 2000/XP. There is no support for Windows 9x
        </p>
      <subsection name="Set up Windows 2000" >
        <ol>
          <li>Open the <b>Control Panel</b> window using Start -->Settings-->Control Panel. </li>
          <li>In "Control Panel" window, invoke <b>Regional Options</b> icon to open
              "Regional Options" dialog </li>
          <li>In the <b>Regional Options</b> dialog, put a check for <b>Vietnamese</b> in
              the <b>Language settings for the system</b> (you need to scroll down
              to the option). Hit OK and Window 2000 will install Vietnamese language support.
              Prepare to have Windows 2000 installation CD ready. Restart your PC if asked.
              This step installs the software. </li>
           <li>In the Input Locale tab, add <b>VI</b> for Vietnamese support.
               This step activates Vietnamese support. </li>
         </ol>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Set up Windows XP" >
        <ol>
           <li>Open the <b>Regional and Language Option</b> dialog using Start -->
               Control Panel --> Date, Time, Language, and Regional Options -->
               Regional and Language Option  </li>
           <li>In the Regional and Language Option dialog's Language tab, place a
               check for <b>Install files for complex script and right to left language…</b>
               and hit OK. Window XP will install a set of languages including Vietnamese.
               Prepare to have Windows XP installation CD ready. Restart your PC if asked. </li>
           <li>In the Regional and Language Option dialog's Language tab, hit
               <b>Details…</b> button to open <b>Text services and input language</b>”
               dialog. In this dialog, hit <b>Add</b> button in <b>Installed Services</b>
               box to open <b>Add Input Language</b> dialog and select <b>Vietnamese</b>
               and <b>US</b> for <b>Input Language</b> and <b>Keyboard Layout...</b>
               respectively. Hit <b>OK</b></li>
        </ol>
      </subsection>
    </section>

    <section name="Usage">
      <p>After adding Vietnamese language support to your Windows system, you should see
         <b>EN</b> (English) in the lower right task bar. Use Left-ALT Shift to
         toggle between <b>EN</b> and <b>VI</b> (Vietnamese)
         In <b>VI</b> mode:
         <ul>
           <li> numbers from 0 to 9 stand for đ, ă, â, ê, ô, ̀, ̉, ̃, ́, and ̣</li>
           <li> [ and ] stand for ư and ơ. </li>
           <li> Use normal shift key for capitalization.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>



